# **MD.SHAHED HASAN**

Address: Flat: A3, House: 63, Road: 3, Block: B, Niketan Housing

Society, Gulshan-1, Dhaka 1212, Bangladesh. Mobile No: 01922120665, 01730058002

e-mail: rtn.shahed@gmail.com



## **Career Objective:**

Administration & Human Resource Management and Development, Organizational Development in Corporate Houses, National, International or Multinational Organizations as Top level executive.

#### **Career Summary:**

Lecturer-CU, Research Consultant-UNESCO, Counselor-HR- Leicester County Council-UK, German International Development Agency (GTZ which is now GiZ), Different positions of HR, Admin &IT/MIS in Seven Group of Companies & Corporate Houses (Lalmai Group, Aman Group, Ejab Group, Concord Group & Navana Group, Abdul Monem Group). Last Position: Director-HR, Rupayan Group.

### **Special Qualification: Key Skills**

#### a. <u>HR & OD</u>

General HR including Recruitment, Selection & Placement, Attendance Management, Leave Management, Payroll Management etc. HRIS HR Analytics. Job Analysis & Manpower Planning KPI & KRA Organizational Development Coaching, Counseling and Motivation Strategic HR Planning Training & Development Development and updating of Policies/ SOPs, Procedures and Systems Performance Management including Performance Appraisal (Promotion, Increment etc.) Reward Management, Leadership Development & Talent Management HR Budgeting in line with Annual Business Plan (ABP) of the Organization. Compensation & Benefits Succession Planning

### b. **ADMINISTRATION**

Disciplinary issues

Safety, security, Cleanliness
Admin Budgeting in line with Annual Business Plan of the Organization.
Vehicle Management
Accommodation & Asset Management
Protocol & PR
Event Management
Stationary & Supply
Work place Discipline including Dress Code
Labor Union Management
Statutory Compliance
c. IT/MIS

Management of IT/MIS department Customizing HRIS Data module HR Analytics database Dashboard Reporting & BI Paperless office

### **Employment History:**

## Total Year of Experience: 26.3 Year(s)

- 1. Rupayan Group- Director HR -2 January 2019- 30 October 2019
- 2. Abdul Monem Group- CHRO & Head of Admin- 11January 2018 to 24 December 2018
- 3. Navana Group- Head of HR, Admin & IT/MIS -15 October 2014 to 10 January 2018.
- 4. Concord Group Head of HR- 01 October 2011 to 12 October 2014
- 5. Ejab Group- Head of HR & Admin- 01 February 2008 to 30 September 2011
  6. Aman Group- Manager Training & Development- 04 January 2004 to 31 January 2008
- 7. Lalmai Group- Manager HR & Admin 15 February 2000 to 31 December 2003
- 8. GTZ (GiZ)- Consultant Training & Development -02 April 1997 to 31 December 1999
- 9. BCEP, Leicester UK- Counselor 18 February 1993 to 31 December 1996
- 10. UNESCO-Dhaka, Research Consultant -01 January 1991 to 15 September 1991
- 11. Chittagong University- Lecturer Dept of Fishery & Limnology 01 January 1990 to 01 December 1990

## **Academic Qualification:**

- 1. PGDHRM-University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, UK- 1992
- 2. M.Sc (Thesis) Fresh water Biology, Chittagong University-1989 First Class First
- 3. B.Sc( Hons.) Zoology, Chittagong University -1988- First Class 3<sup>rd</sup>
- 4. HSC (Science) Gurudayal Govt. College Kishoregonj -1985 2<sup>nd</sup> Division
- 5. SSC ( Agriculture) Kishoregonj Govt. Boys' High School-1983 First Division, 6<sup>th</sup> position

### **Training Summary:**

- 1. HR as Strategic Business Partner from HSPP Dhaka-2016 (4 days)
- 2. Effective Organizational Development Strategy from BIM Dhaka -2015 (3 days)
- 3. Six Sigma from BIM Dhaka -2014 ( 5 days)
- 4. Bangladesh Labor Law from BIM Dhaka-2012 ( 6 days)
- 5. Talent Acquisition & Management from BIM Dhaka- 2012 (5days)
- Team Building from Ananda Bazar Group, India-2011 (3 days)
- 7. Manager & His Job from BARD Comilla -1997 (3 days)
- 8. Project Evaluation & Management from The University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, UK-1992 (12 weeks evening course)
- 9. Development Banking & Financial Management from The University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, UK-1992 (12 weeks evening course)
- 10. English for the Professionals from The British Council, Dhaka -1990 (12 weeks)

## **Specialization:**

Have working experience in HR, & Admin of the following industries: Corporate Houses/ Group of Companies. FMCG, Real Estate, Construction, Developer, Mega Projects (Infrastructure development) RMG, Beverage, Manufacturing, Trading, Agro based industries, Donner Agencies of NGOs, ICT farms, Ice Cream & Milk Products, Frozen & Non-Frozen Foods, Power Plant, Economic Zone, Consulting Farms etc.

### **Extra Curricular Activities:**

- Member Rotary International b. Life Member Bangladesh Kidney Foundation,
  - c. Life Member Help The Needy, d. Member British Scholars Association,
  - e. Member Zoological Society of Bangladesh.

#### **Language Proficiency:**

Excellent interpersonal skills in Bangla and English. Can understand and speak Hindi

# **Personal Information:**

Father's Name : Late Md. Ibrahim Mazumder Mother's Name : Alhaj Late Kamrunnessa Begum

Date of Birth : August 7, 1968

Gender : Male Marital Status : Married Nationality : Bangladeshi

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address : 557, Women's College Road, Adarsha Sadar, Cumilla-3500, Bangladesh.

Current Location : Dhaka

**References:** will be provided, if required.